A Guide to the Population Council records, Public Information Office and Publications, Accession 2, RG 2, Series 14 FA1434
Rockefeller Archive Center
Population Council records, Public Information Office and Publications, Accession 2, RG 2, Series 14
1965-1980
Rockefeller Archive Center
Population Council
FA1434
19.45 Cubic Feet 23 letter-size document boxes, 20 legal-size document boxes, 1 standard record storage box
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Biographical / Historical
The Population Council was founded by John D. Rockefeller 3rd in 1952 to undertake "significant activities in the broad field of population." Its goal has been to bring about a reduction in the number of births that occur in the world. In its early years, the business of the Population Council was conducted by a Demographic Division and a Biomedical Division. Through its Demographic Division, the Council sought to document what it conceived to be an overpopulation problem threatening many areas of the world. To accomplish this purpose, the Division facilitated research on the economic, social, and psychological factors which affect the growth and decline of human population. This Council-assisted research effort was conducted not only by staff of the Demographic Division but also by other institutions and scholars, some of whom received Council grants and fellowships and some of whom received informal advice and consultation on how to design and execute studies.
The Biomedical Division, which, beginning in 1959, occupied a laboratory at The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (now The Rockefeller University), has conducted pure and applied research on plant, animal, and human reproductive physiology and on the development, the physiological action, and the safety and effectiveness of contraceptive methods. The Council facilitated similar types of medical research by non-Council scientists at other institutions by giving grants and fellowships for such research. The Council's biomedical research and its support for research by non-Council scientists were instrumental in the development of the modern intrauterine coil and the birth control pill.
In about 1960, the scope of Population Council activities expanded. The Council began to render practical and technical aid to foreign nations. Beginning in that year, the Demographic Division, in addition to supervising research, became involved in Pakistan's family planning program, extending practical and technical aid in organizing and running a national family planning program. By 1964 the Council's Demographic Division had assisted in organizing family planning programs in South Korea, Taiwan, Thailand, Tunisia, and Turkey. In that year, the Council created the Technical Assistance Division. This division, in ensuing years, continued the assistance of the Council in the countries where it had already become involved and also helped start and run programs in India, Morocco, the Philippines, and Puerto Rico.
An underlying aim of the Council's grant programs has been to encourage the development and growth of institutions that would promote family planning programs. To this end, the Council has given grants and advice to various universities and research centers for starting and upgrading programs for demographic and biomedical training and research programs; has assisted the United Nations to set up and expand regional Demographic Training and Research Centres in Bombay, India, Santiago, Chile, and Cairo, Egypt; has worked with the Ford Foundation on family planning programs in Pakistan, India, and North Africa.
In addition to rendering technical aid and sponsoring research, the Council has undertaken several complementary public relations efforts. To reach the general populations of the United States and of foreign nations, Council officers have worked to inform the mass media about population issues and to encourage magazine articles, movies, and books dealing with population matters. Council officers and representatives have also made trips and prepared reports to convince various foreign government leaders of the importance and the desirability of promulgating family planning programs. In addition, Council officers participated in and helped organize and finance conferences for demographers and medical scientists active in population work.
The Population Council has obtained its financial support through large contributions. The Ford and Rockefeller Foundations and the Rockefeller Brothers Fund have been the principal institutional supporters of the Council. John D. Rockefeller 3rd has been the single most significant individual backer of the Council.
Arrangement
The Public Information Office and Publications files are arranged in eight subseries, by record type or program, as follows:
Subseries 1: Country Profiles
Subseries 2: Publications - General Files
Subseries 3: French Translation Project
Subseries 4: Spanish Translation Project
Subseries 5: Reports Files
Subseries 6: Basic Library Program (Basic Books)
Subseries 7: Population Council Annual Reports
Subseries 8: Books and Occasional Papers Program
Scope and Contents
The bulk of the Public Information Office records document the translation program, including primarily the French translation project, and to a lesser extent the Spanish translation project.
Publications files are also extensive, primarily documenting the creation of Reports, as well as the Books and Occasional Papers program. Files often include: project administration files, background research, correspondence, notes and early drafts, as well as budgets, and distribution and marketing records
- Public Information Office and Publications, 1965-1980; 14
  - Country Profiles, 1
    - Afghanistan (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Algeria (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bangladesh (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Barbados (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Botswana (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Canada (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Chile (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - China (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Colombia (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Costa Rica (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Cuba (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Dahomey (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Dominican Republic (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Ecuador (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Egypt (U.A.R.) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - El Salvador (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Ethiopia (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Fiji (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Finland (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - France (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Germany (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Ghana (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Ghana (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Guadeloupe (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Guatemala (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Haiti (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Honduras (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Hong Kong (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Hungary (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - India (Box 2, Folder 30-31)
    - Indonesia (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Iran (Box 2, Folder 33-35)
    - Iraq (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Israel (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Jamaica (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Japan (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Korea (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Lebanon (Box 3, Folder 41-42)
    - Malaysia (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Mali (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Mauritius (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Morocco (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Nepal (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Netherlands (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - New Zealand (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Nicaragua (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Nigeria (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Pakistan (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Peru (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Philippines (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Portugal (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Puerto Rico (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Rwanda (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Senegal (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Sierra Leone (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Singapore (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Somali (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Sri Lanka (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Sweden (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Syria (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Taiwan (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Tanzania (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Thailand (Box 4, Folder 67-68)
    - Togo (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Tunisia (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Turkey (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Uganda (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - United Kingdom (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - United States (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Venezuela (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Vietnam (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - Zaire (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - Zambia (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - Italy (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - Country Profiles - General (Box 5, Folder 79A)
  - Publications - General Files, 2
    - ICARP Bulletin - General (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - ICARP Bulletin - Design (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - ICARP Bulletin - Distribution (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - ICARP Bulletin - Vol. 1, No. 1 (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - ICARP Bulletin - No. 2 (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - ICARP Bulletin - No. 3 (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - ICARP Bulletin - No. 4 (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - ICARP Bulletin - No. 5, 1980 September (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - ICARP - Brochure (Box 5, Folder 88)
    - Blue Cover Reprint Series, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Sivin - Follow-Up Survey Handbook (Box 5, Folder 90)
    - Tietze - Fact Book 1979 (Box 5, Folder 91)
    - Tietze - Abortion Fact Book Supplement (Box 5, Folder 92)
    - Nortman-Hofstatter - Fact Book, 9th Edition (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - Chen-Fawcett - Public Policy and Population Change in Sinapore, 1977 September (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - Alumni Information Series (Box 6, Folder 95-96)
    - AID - French Translation Program (Box 6, Folder 97)
    - AID - Spanish Translation Program (Box 6, Folder 98)
    - World Population Year - Various Publications (Box 6, Folder 99)
    - World Population Year - Special Report by Berelson, 1973 January (Box 7, Folder 100)
    - World Population Conference, Bucharest (Box 7, Folder 101)
    - World Population Year Tribune (Box 7, Folder 102)
    - Publications - General, 1971-1974 (Box 24, Folder 312)
    - Population Council - Annual Report, 1968-1978 (Box 24, Folder 313-323)
    - Population Council Brochure, 1977-1978 (Box 25, Folder 324-326)
    - Periodical Sales Program - Procedures, 1971-1973 (Box 25, Folder 327)
    - Distribution of Books, 1970-1975 (Box 25, Folder 328)
    - Miscellaneous Published Brochures (Box 25, Folder 329)
    - Phasing Out of Current Publications, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 330)
    - Developed Country Survey, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 331)
    - Field Staff Questionnaire, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 332)
    - Country Profiles - General (Box 25, Folder 333)
    - Field Staff Meetings, New York, 1975 April (Box 25, Folder 334)
    - Library Survey, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 335)
    - Field Staff Mailings by Information Office, 1973-1977 (Box 25, Folder 336)
    - Description of Key People Materials (Box 25, Folder 337)
    - Reports on Population-Family Planning (Box 25, Folder 338)
    - Invitation to University Preses for Population Council Book Publishing, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 339)
    - Basic Library Program, Book Distribution Program - General Correspondence (Box 26, Folder 340)
    - Focus - The Years Ahead, 1977 November (Box 26, Folder 341)
    - Focus - Contraceptives, 1977 November (Box 26, Folder 342)
    - Grants in Demography 1974-1975 - Brochure (Box 26, Folder 343)
    - Country Profiles - Disposition, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 344)
    - Population Atlas (Demeny) (Box 27, Folder 345)
    - Directory of Fellows (Box 27, Folder 346)
    - Fellowship Brochure (Box 27, Folder 347)
    - Demographic Division Program Notes, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 348)
    - Population Chronicle (Box 27, Folder 349)
    - Keeny Newsletter, No. 49-68, 1971-1974 (Box 27, Folder 350)
    - Population Council Newsletter, 1966-1969 (Box 27, Folder 351)
    - Permission to Reprint from Population Council Publications, 1969-1971 (Box 27, Folder 352)
  - French Translation Project, 3
    - Project 1 - Use of Oral Contraceptives, Mauldin-Jones, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 103)
    - Project 2 - The Population of Tropical Africa, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 104)
    - Project 3 - Family Planning Programs, Berelson, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 105)
    - Project 4 - IUD Retention, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 106)
    - Project 5 - Contraceptive Technology, Segal-Tietze, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 107)
    - Project 6 - On Communications Aspects, Ecafe W.G., 1970 (Box 7, Folder 108)
    - Project 7 - USSR - Views on Population, Studies No. 49, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 109)
    - Project 8 - Studies No. 50 - U.S. Papal Encyclical and Catholic Practice, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 110)
    - Project 9 - Country Profiles - Pakistan, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 111)
    - Project 10 - Country Profiles - U.A.R., 1970 (Box 7, Folder 112)
    - Project 11 - Country Profiles - Sierra Leone, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 113)
    - Project 12-17 - Current Publications, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 114)
    - Project 18 - Country Profiles - Iran, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 114A)
    - Project 19 - Reports - Governmental Policy Statements on Population, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 114B)
    - Project 20 - National Family Planning Programs, Berelson, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 115)
    - Project 21 - KAP Manual, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 116)
    - Project 22 - Macy Conference, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 117)
    - Project 23 - Studies No. 51 - Turkey - Changes in Birth Control Practices, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 118)
    - Project 24 - Family Planning - A Teaching Guide for Nurses, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 119)
    - Project 25 - Studies in Family Planning, No. 52, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 120)
    - Project 26 - Current Publications, No. 7, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 121)
    - Project 27 - Studies No. 53 - Abortion, Obtained and Denied, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 122)
    - Project 28 - Studies in Family Planning, No. 54, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 123)
    - Project 29 - Studies in Family Planning, No. 55 - Evaluation of IUDs, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 124)
    - Project 30 - Commercial Products and Distribution of Contraceptives, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 125)
    - Project 31 - Voluntary Sterilization, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 126)
    - Project 32 - 1970 Fact Book (Box 8, Folder 127)
    - Project 33 - Studies in Family Planning, No. 56 - Japan, India, Hawaii KAP, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 128)
    - Project 34 - Studies in Family Planning, No. 57 - Present State of Family Planning Practice, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 129)
    - Project 35 - Studies in Family Planning, No. 58 - Morocco-Rural KAP, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 130)
    - Project 36 - Country Profiles - Ghana, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 131)
    - Project 37 - Studies in Family Planning, No. 59, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 132)
    - Project 38 - Studies in Family Planning, No. 60, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 133)
    - Project 39 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol. 2, No. 1, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 134)
    - Project 40 - Ghana Population Census (Translation of Volume 5), 1971 (Box 8, Folder 135)
    - Project 41 - Reports, No. 6 - Population Growth and Economic Welfare, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 136)
    - Project 42 - Interim Report of U.S. President's Commission, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 137)
    - Project 43 - Country Profiles - Japan, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 138)
    - Project 44 - Segal and Atkinson, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 139)
    - Project 45 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol. 2, No. 2, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 140)
    - Project 46 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol. 2, No. 3, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 141)
    - Project 47 - Country Profiles - Jamaica, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 142)
    - Project 48 - Country Profiles - Indonesia, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 143)
    - Project 49 - Reports, No. 7, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 144)
    - Project 50 - Studies in Family Planning, Index 51-60, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 145)
    - Project 51 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol. 2, No. 4, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 146)
    - Project 52 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol. 2, No. 5, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 147)
    - Project 53 - Reports, No. 2, Third Edition, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 148)
    - Project 54 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol. 2, No. 7, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 149)
    - Project 55 - Mauldin and Lapham - An Assessment of National Family Planning Programs, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 150)
    - Project 56 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol. 2, No. 6, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 151)
    - Project 57 - Population and Family Planning in the People's Republic of China, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 152)
    - Shryock and Siegel - The Methods and Materials of Demography (Box 8, Folder 153)
    - Project 58 - Population Dynamics and Family Planning, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 154)
    - French Translations (Box 9, Folder 155)
    - French Translations - Studies in Family Planning No. 18 (Box 9, Folder 156)
    - French Translations - Studies in Family Planning No. 22 (Box 9, Folder 157)
    - French Translations - Studies in Family Planning No. 24 (Box 9, Folder 158)
    - French Translations - Studies in Family Planning No. 34 (Box 9, Folder 159)
    - Project 63 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol 2, No. 8, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 160)
    - Project 64 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol 2, No. 9, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 161)
    - Project 65 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol 2, No. 10, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 162)
    - Project 66 - Reports, No. 9, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 163)
    - Project 67 - Reports, No. 10, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 164)
    - Project 68 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol 2, No. 11, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 165)
    - Project 69 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol 2, No. 12, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 166)
    - Project 70 - Country Profiles - Trinadad and Tobago, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 167)
    - Project 71 - Country Profiles - Kenya, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 168)
    - Project 72 - Reports, No. 1 (1971 Edition) (Box 9, Folder 169)
    - Project 76 - Reports, No. 11 (Box 9, Folder 170)
    - Project 77 - Catalog of French Translations (Box 9, Folder 171)
    - Project 78 - Reports, No. 11 (Box 9, Folder 172)
    - Project 79 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol 3, No. 3 (Box 9, Folder 173)
    - Project 59 - Lapham, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 173A)
    - Caldwell - French Translation (Box 10, Folder 173B)
    - Caldwell - French Translation (Box 10, Folder 174)
    - Project 61 - Fawcett - Psychology and Population, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 175)
    - Project 62 - Reports, No. 8, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 176)
    - Project 73 - Country Profiles - Israel, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 177)
    - Project 74 - Studies in Family Planning - Index, Vol. 2, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 178)
    - Project 75 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol 3, No. 1 (Box 10, Folder 179)
    - Project 80 - Country Profiles - Thailand (Box 10, Folder 180)
    - Project 81 - Country Profiles - Nepal (Box 10, Folder 181)
    - Project 82 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol 3, No. 4 (Box 10, Folder 182)
    - Project 83 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol 3, No. 5 (Box 10, Folder 183)
    - Project 84 - Country Profiles - France (Box 10, Folder 184)
    - Project 85 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol 3, No. 6 (Box 10, Folder 185)
    - Project 86 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol 3, No. 7 (Box 10, Folder 186)
    - Project 87 - Population Association of Africa (Box 10, Folder 187)
    - Project 88 - Are Our Descendants Doomed (Box 10, Folder 188)
    - Project 89 - Population and the American Future (Box 10, Folder 189)
    - Project 90 - Davis, Hugh - The IUD (Box 11, Folder 190-191)
    - Project 91 - Manisoff, M. (Box 11, Folder 192)
    - Project 92 - Ominde and Ejiogu - Population Growth and Economic Development in Africa (Box 11, Folder 193)
    - Project 93 - Country Profiles - Sweden (Box 11, Folder 194)
    - Project 94 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol. 3, No. 7 (Supplement), 1972 July (Box 11, Folder 195)
    - Project 95 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol. 3, No. 8, 1972 August (Box 11, Folder 196)
    - Project 96 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol. 3, No. 9, 1972 September (Box 11, Folder 197)
    - Project 97 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol. 3, No. 10, 1972 October (Box 11, Folder 198)
    - Project 98 - Fact Book 1972 (Box 11, Folder 199)
    - Project 99 - Country Profiles - Iran (Box 11, Folder 200)
    - Project 100 - Fendall - WHO Correspondence on Sale (Box 11, Folder 201)
    - Project 100 - Fendall - Auxilliaries in Health Care (Box 11, Folder 202)
    - Project 101 - Postcard (Box 11, Folder 203)
    - Project 102 - Reports, No. 12, 1972 October (Box 12, Folder 204)
    - Project 103 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol. 3, No. 11, 1972 November (Box 12, Folder 205)
    - Project 104 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol. 3, No. 12, 1972 December (Box 12, Folder 206)
    - Project 105 - Berelson - Population Policy in Developing Countries (Box 12, Folder 207)
    - Project 106 - Caldwell - The Changing American Family (Box 12, Folder 208)
    - Project 108-165 - Miscellaneous Projects (Box 12, Folder 209)
    - Project 109-73 - Frejka - Future of Population Growth, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 210)
    - Project 113-73 - Cohn and Lieberman - Family Planning and Health, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 211)
    - Project 114-73 - Mauldin - Beyond Family Planning, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 212)
    - Projects 116-73 through 120-73 - Studies, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 213)
    - Project 123-73 - Catalog, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 214)
    - Project 125-73 - Commercial Distribution of Contraceptives, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 215)
    - Project 127-73 - Articles on Supreme Court Decision on Abortion, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 216)
    - Project 107-73 - Country Profiles - Morocco, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 217)
    - Project 128-73 - Muslim Attitudes Toward Family Planning, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 218)
    - Project 137-73 - The Population Explosion - A Christian Concern, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 219)
    - Project 138-73 - Seltzer - Demo Data Collection, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 220)
    - Project 139-73 - Kocher - Rural Development, Income Distribution and Fertility Decline, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 221)
    - Project 142-73 - Reports, No. 14 - Tietze, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 222)
    - Project 145-74 - Berelson - Book, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 223)
    - Project 168 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol. 6, No. 2, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 224)
    - Project 169 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol. 6, No. 3, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 225)
    - Project 170 - Castadot and Rosenfield - Early Postpartum, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 226)
    - Project 171 - Sivin Book, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 227)
    - Project 172 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol. 6, No. 4, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 228)
    - Project 173 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol. 6, No. 5, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 229)
    - Project 174 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol. 6, No. 6, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 230)
    - Project 175 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol. 6, No. 7, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 231)
    - Project 176 - Studies in Family Planning, Vol. 6, No. 8, 1975 August (Box 13, Folder 232)
    - Correspondence with Pierre Pradervand, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 233)
    - AID Grant, csd-2508 (Box 13, Folder 234)
    - AID Grant, csd-1175 (Box 13, Folder 235)
    - 1976 Production Statements (Box 13, Folder 236)
    - Project Statements, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 237)
    - Project Statements, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 238)
    - French Program 1975-1976 Status Reports (Box 14, Folder 239)
    - French Program 1973-1974 Status Reports (Box 14, Folder 240)
    - French Program 1970-1972 Status Reports (Box 14, Folder 241)
    - Legal - French (Box 14, Folder 242)
    - Harcourt Correspondence, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 243)
    - Harcourt Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 14, Folder 244)
    - Contract with Gustave Harcourt (Box 14, Folder 245)
    - Bourgeois-Pichat - Project Revision, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 246)
    - Bourgeois-Pichat - Project Revision, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 247)
    - Bourgeois-Pichat - Project Revision, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 248)
    - Bourgeois-Pichat, 1970 September-1971 (Box 14, Folder 249)
    - Bourgeois-Pichat - Annual Honorarium for Revision (Box 15, Folder 250)
    - French Subcomittee - General and Meetings (Box 15, Folder 251)
    - Harcourt Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 15, Folder 252)
    - French Translations - Evaluation - Payments (Box 15, Folder 253)
    - French Translations - Evaluation, 1974-1975 (Box 15, Folder 254)
    - French Translations - Evaluation, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 255)
    - French Translations - Fundraising (Box 15, Folder 256)
    - French Translation - Subcomittee (Box 16, Folder 257)